PROFILE

I have always walked the line between art and science. I've always applied creative and design thinking to my life, family, and work. In questioning and rethinking common approaches and business processes, innovation often takes shape. In my career, technology has imposed a consistent newness. This newness has surfaced in how we communicate, shop, engage and digest information.

Being at the forefront of digital experience delivery, I have had the opportunity to shape the everyday engagement of our customers. Core to my personal mission is my direct work with analysts, content creators, and developers to help demonstrate how those roles are central to experience creation and delivery.

I have strong technical and communications skills and they have always served me well in my endeavors. With years of success in development, marketing technology, and digital experience, I have a proven track record reimagining programs and processes to address today's ever-changing business world.

EXAMPLES OF LEADERSHIP

- Developed a new career path within field sales focused completely on driving technology adoption and value realization of Adobe's mature enterprise customers.
- Created a measurable framework for technology Adoption used by Solution Consulting to support sales renewal activities.
- Delivered customer focused Adoption Workshops that surface priorities and technical work streams for execution.

EXPERIENCE

Adobe Systems, Lehi, Utah (1/2007 – Present)

Customer Success Architect, Principal (5/2018 – Present)

Work with internal teams and customers to devise programs and strategies to drive technology adoption. Use design thinking strategies to develop technical workshops focused on tactical outcomes for enterprise customers. Deliver customer workshops focused around experience delivery, architecture and best practices.

Solutions Consultant, Principal (2/2015 – 4/2017)

Work with field sales teams to create multi-solution selling strategies. Work with customers and prospects to discuss technical deployment plans and with current digital marketing infrastructure. Support sales cycle to deliver solution tailored presentation to customer executive teams.

Solution Architect, Media & Entertainment Strategy (8/2012 – 2/2015)

Develop & deploy multiproduct solutions for enterprise customers. Demonstrate cross-network value realization for executive stakeholders. Lead a team of product specific consultants to deliver against a solution roadmap.

Act as cross-functional lead developing consulting solution offerings to compliment Adobe Marketing Cloud products. Work with Product Management and Product Marketing to communicate and assess services needs and opportunities. Socialize and train consulting force on new Consulting offerings.

Client portfolio includes Conde Nast, Viacom, ESPN, Comcast, Disney, Time, Inc., Sports Illustrated and PayPal.

Lamont Crook

Principal Consultant, Media & Entertainment Team Lead (9/2010 – 8/2012)

Work with enterprise media clients. Architect digital analytics solution and work with development teams to deploy. Develop technical guides based on business interviews. Manage project life cycle from deployment to commencement. Create new documentation and tools to track more robust metrics, streamline implementations, and clarify procedures with clients.

Program Architect, Genesis Solutions (5/2009 – 8/2010)

Develop and implement a methodology and process for developing partner applications in the newly developed developer sandbox. Worked directly with strategic partners to architect and implement data exchange utilizing SOAP and REST protocols.

Senior Consultant, Retail Team Lead (1/2007 – 4/2009)

Assist client to implement code throughout their website and perform quality checks to ensure that implementation has been completed thoroughly and meets their strategic business needs. Design and develop a tool for tracking multiple marketing campaigns across visits, which will assist marketing professionals in understanding the participation of multiple campaigns in a conversion.

Manage a team of consultants. Spearheaded the editing the writing of the *Retail Playbook* used for implementations with all retail clients. Client portfolio includes Nike, Wal-mart, PayPal, Amazon, BestBuy and GSI Commerce.

Decorative Product Source, Goshen, New York (2/2005 - 12/2007)

Manager, Database Marketing (1/2006 - 12/2007)

Analyze and participate-in strategic marketing efforts to grow professional business and to develop strategic targets in consumer business. Develop consumer models to predict the profiles that would develop the greatest yield and highest conversion. Write analysis of customer behavior to help project the impact of design and architecture changes to the web site. Assist in managing online keyword spending by developing models necessary to develop bid strategies based on keyword ROI and A/S trends. Develop strategies to manage keywords based upon traffic trends on an hour by hour and day by day basis to most effectively leverage budgets.

Administer at the corporate level Omniture's Site Catalyst web analytics tool. Develop reporting to track campaigns across multiple creative endeavors. Interface with Omniture's technical and Best Practices team to site-specific behavior. Present Omniture's features and potential to marketing, merchandising, and operations in to demonstrate and strategize as to how to best apply web analytics to their specific department. Manage corporate CSE spend. Develop, maintain and monitor product feeds. Manipulate spend and product selection based on sales and budget goals. Develop and maintain corporate marketing web-based system responsible for reporting all demand sales and order activity both online and off.

Perl Web Developer (2/2005 - 1/2006)

Responsible for coding enhancements and bug fixes for both external web sites and internal order processing system built in a proprietary perl object system. Researched user requests and specifications for feature improvements and bug fixes and implemented fixes for Quality Assurance.

Δwards

Top Contributor to Field, Professional Services 2013

Speaking Engagements & Blog Posts

2015, 2013, 2012, 2010, 2008 Adobe Summit, Salt Lake City, UT 2012, 2011 Adobe Exchange, Las Vegas, NV 2009 Pluck Socialize Customer Conference (September, 2009) Austin, TX http://blogs.adobe.com/digitalmarketing/author/lamont/

Lamont Crook

https://developer.omniture.com/en US/user/3518

EDUCATION

Columbia University, New York, New York Technology Management Graduate Program (2003) Maintained 3.9 GPA

Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, Master of Arts (1997 Unfinished)

Sarah Lawrence College, Bronxville, New York, Master of Fine Arts (1996) Maintained 3.8 GPA

Bethel College, St. Paul, Minnesota, Bachelor of Arts Maintained 3.4. GPA

PATENTS

"Aggregated web analytics request systems and methods," U.S. Patent 8301645, filed 08/26/2010, issued 10/30/2012.

"Genesis Enablement Object," U.S. Patent 9,141,611, filed 10/29/2012, issued 09/22/2015.